vast.com 2017-06-07

# Privacy Policy - Vast.com, Inc.

This privacy policy addresses our data collection and use practices.  By continuing to use Vast.com, you agree to these terms.  This policy only applies to your use of the Vast.com website as an unregistered user.  This policy does not apply to our business partners, including our API partners.  Vast.com offers some users access to message boards, and this policy does not apply to those, either.  You have rights under California Civil Code §1798.83 to learn more about our disclosure of your personal data; to exercise those rights, contact [privacy@vast.com](mailto:privacy@vast.com).  The effective date of this policy is December 7, 2007.

**Data You Voluntarily Provide.** You may have opportunities to express interest in, or register for, third parties’ offerings.  If you do so, we will follow your instructions about providing your data to the third party (and we might retain the data as well).  Also, if you participate in any surveys, we treat your survey responses like we treat our other business records.

**Data We Collect Automatically.** As part of our servers’ normal operations, we log IP addresses and referring/destination URLs.  We use this data, as well as other server usage data, to analyze site and user behavior, troubleshoot technical problems, resolve disputes, address complaints and prepare aggregated reports that we share with others.  We and our third party vendors (such as our web analytics service provider) may use cookies and web beacons to analyze site usage, target ads, improve our site and personalize your experience (including tracking your site usage to do so).

**Other Data Collection.** We may get data from or about you in other ways not specifically described in this statement.  For example, you might contact Customer Service, or we may get a third party complaint about you.  We handle this data like other business records.

**Contractors/Service Providers.** Third party contractors may have access to our databases.  Usually these contractors sign a standard confidentiality agreement.

Some of our site’s functionality may be operated by third party service providers, and in the course of providing this functionality, these service providers may obtain some of your personal data from you directly or transferred from us to facilitate your usage of this service.  Usually we require these providers to use and disclose your personal data only as necessary to perform their services.

We use third-party advertising companies and advertising networks to serve ads to you on our behalf when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.  If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>.

**Our “Corporate Family.”** We may share your data with any parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, other entities under a common control or third party acquirers. We expect these other entities will honor this policy.  Also, we may allow a potential acquirer or merger partner to review our databases, although we would restrict their use and disclosure of this data during the diligence phase.

**Government Relations and Lawsuits.** We may disclose data about you to the government if we are required to do so or if we think the disclosure is appropriate; and you authorize these disclosures.  We may also disclose data about you in connection with actual or potential legal proceedings (a) if we are required to do so, (b) if such disclosures might mitigate our liability, or (c) to enforce our rights.

**Communicating with Other Users.** You may not collect (manually or in an automated manner) any data (including personal data or email addresses) from our site.

**Children.** If you are 12 and under, do not use the site or provide any data to us.

**Limits on Our Abilities.** Our site is very complicated, so we might inadvertently use or disclose your data in ways inconsistent with this policy.  For example, a temporary software glitch could lead to an unexpected public display of data.  We might also make ad hoc uses of your data in ways not mentioned here.  In these anomalous situations, your sole remedy is that we will try to rectify the anomaly as soon as we can.

**Security.** We use industry-standard security protocols, such as (if and where we think appropriate) firewalls and restrictions on which employees can access user data.  However, perfect security does not exist on the Internet.

**Amendment.** We may amend this policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site, which automatically take effect 30 days after initial posting.
